# Jun Xing (邢骏)

junxnui@gmail.com, http://junxnui.github.io

# RESEARCH

My research combines modern concepts in computer graphics, computer vision, machine learning and human computer interaction, with broad applications in 2D/3D digital contents analysis, synthesis and authoring. In particular, I am interested in *interactive/predictive* modeling and *deep learning-based* reconstruction of high-fidelity face, hair and body for digital human.

# **EDUCATION**

University of Hong Kong	2012.09-2016.12
PhD in computer science, advised by Dr. Li-Yi Wei	
University of Science and Technology of China (USTC)	2008.09 - 2012.06
Bachelor in Electronic Engineering and Information	

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

USC Institute for Creative Technologies	2017.05 — present
Postdoctoral researcher, Vision and Graphics Lab, Los Angeles	
Adobe Research	2016.07—2016.09
Graphics research intern, Procedural Imaging Group, San Jose	
Autodesk Research	2016.01 - 2016.04
HCI Graphics research intern, UI Group, Toronto	
Microsoft Research Asia	2014.12-2015.04
Graphics research intern, Visual Computing Group, Beijing	

# **PUBLICATIONS**

#### [10] paGAN: Real-time Avatars Using Dynamic Textures,

Koki Nagano, Jaewoo Seo, Lingyu Wei, *Jun Xing*, Shunsuke Saito, Zimo Li, Aviral Agarwal, Jens Fursund, Hao Li *SIGGRAPH Asia 2018* 

#### [9] HairNet: Single-View Hair Reconstruction using Convolutional Neural Networks

Yi Zhou, Liwen Hu, *Jun Xing*, Weikai Chen, Han-Wei Kung, Xin Tong, Hao Li *ECCV 2018* 

#### [8] Deep Volumetric Video From Very Sparse Multi-View Performance Capture

Zeng Huang, Tianye Li, Weikai Chen, Yajie Zhao, *Jun Xing*, Chloe LeGendre, Linjie Luo, Chongyang Ma, Hao Li *ECCV 2018* 

## [7] Identity Preserving Face Completion for Large Ocular Region Occlusio.

Yajie Zhao, Weikai Chen, *Jun Xing*, Xiaoming Li, Zach Bessinger, Fuchang Liu, Wangmeng Zuo, Ruigang Yang *BMVC 2018* 

# [6] Autocomplete 3D Sculpting

Mengqi Peng, *Jun Xing*, Li-Yi Wei *SIGGRAPH 2018* 

#### [5] Mesoscopic Facial Geometry Inference using Deep Neural Networks

Loc Huynh, Weikai Chen, Shunsuke Saito, *Jun Xing*, Koki Nagano, Andrew Jones, Hao Li, Paul Debevec *CVPR 2018 (Spotlight)* 

### [4] Sequence-to-Sequence Learning via Shared Latent Representation

Xu Shen, Xinmei Tian, *Jun Xing*, Yong Rui, Dacheng Tao *AAAI 2018* 

#### [3] Energy-Brushes: Interactive Tools for Illustrating Stylized Elemental Dynamics

Jun Xing, Rubaiat Habib Kazi, Tovi Grossman, Li-Yi Wei, Jos Stam, George Fitzmaurice UIST 2016

## [2] Autocomplete Hand-drawn Animations

Jun Xing, Li-Yi Wei, Takaaki Shiratori, and Koji Yatani SIGGRAPH Asia 2015

#### [1] Autocomplete Painting Repetitions

Jun Xing, Hsiang-Ting Chen and Li-Yi Wei SIGGRAPH Asia 2014

#### **EXHIBITIONS**

#### Deep Learning-Based Photoreal Avatars for Online Virtual Worlds in iOS

Koki Nagano, Jaewoo Seo, *Jun Xing*, Kyle San, Aaron Hong, Mclean Goldwhite, Jiale Kuang, Aviral Agarwal, Caleb Arthur, Hanwei Kung, Stuti Rastogi, Carrie Sun, Stephen Chen, Jens Fursund, Hao Li. *SIGGRAPH 2018 Real-time Live!* 

#### MORE RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

#### Strip-based Hair Modeling in VR

2017.08 - present

We provide a 3D VR authoring interface for immersive interaction with the hair models. Our system combines the flexibility of manual authoring, the convenience of data-driven automation for high quality hair modeling.

### Autocomplete VR painting

2016.07 - present

The goal is to handle different types of repetitions in VR painting, including the detail decorative strokes, the surface strokes, and even higher-level scaffold, in a simple and general framework.

## **Interactive Facial Hair Editing and Synthesis**

2017.06 - present

Users can design facial hairs of different shapes/lengths/densities via simple sketching, while keeping the style of a target facial hair defined by an exemplar image.

#### **Perspective Undistortion of Unconstrained Portrait Photos**

2018.03 - present

We present a deep learning-based approach specially tailored for rectifying the facial distortion in an unconstrained portrait image.

#### **Quantization Network**

2018.02 - present

We present a simple/straightforward and general/uniform solution for any-bit weights and activations quantization, yet achieving higher performance than state-of-the-arts.

#### **PATENTS**

#### **Techniques for Generating Dynamic Effects Animations**

US filed by Autodesk (2016)

#### Stroke Operation Prediction for Three-Dimensional Digital Content

US filed by Adobe (2017), Pending

#### ACADEMIC SERVICE

#### **Committee Member:**

**AAAI 2019** 

International Conference on Computational Visual Media (CVM) 2019

Pacific Graphics 2018

SIGGRAPH Emerging Technology 2017

#### **Reviewer:**

SIGGRAPH Asia 2017; CHI 2017; PG 2015, 2016; Computer & Graphics 2017;

IEEE Transactions on Cognitive and Developmental Systems 2017;

IEEE Computer Graphics and Applications 2016;

# PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

# **Designer:**

algorithm, system, UI/UX

# **Programmer:**

C/C++, Qt, Python, Java, OpenGL/CV/VR, Unity

# **AWARDS**

Excellent intern of Stars of Tomorrow Internship Program, Microsoft Research Asia	2015	
HKU University Postgraduate Fellowships, HKU	2012-2015	
Outstanding undergraduate, USTC	2012	
Outstanding undergraduate research project, USTC	2011	
Second prize in Mathematical Contest in Modeling	2011	
National Scholarship, Ministry of Education, China	2011	
National Inspirational Scholarship, Ministry of Education, China	2009, 2010	
Outstanding Students Scholarship, USTC	2008, 2009	

# REFERENCES

Li-Yi WeiAdobe Research, lwei@adobe.comHao LiPinscreen, USC, ICT, hao@hao-li.comRubaiat Habib KaziAdobe Research, rhabib@adobe.com

Tovi Grossman Autodesk Research and University of Toronto, tovi@dgp.toronto.edu